Guide to the Communist Party of the United States of America Audio Collection TAM.132.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Communist Party of the United States of America Audio Collection
Bulk, 1965-1989
1920s - 2002
TAM.132.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
81.0 linear feet (82 boxes)
The Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA) was founded in 1919 by members of the left wing of the Socialist Party USA. The CPUSA, and affiliated organizations, went on to play a prominent role in the labor movement, in the struggle for civil rights for African-Americans, and in many other campaigns and movements. By the 1940s the Party had achieved considerable influence in the Left, but Cold War prosecution and harrassment of the Party, and shifting currents in the international communist movement resulted in a decline in Party strength after the early 1950s. Nevertheless, in the Civil Rights Movement, in the New Left, and in the gender and ethnic politics of the 70s, 80s, and after, the Party continued to play a significant role. This collection is comprised of the miscellaneous audiotapes found at the New York headquarters of the CPUSA in the summer of 2006. Included are recordings of official meetings of the Party at the national level, such as National Conventions, Central Committee and Political Bureau meetings; as well as meetings of district, state, youth and special-interest organizations. Also included are recordings of public meetings, conferences, rallies, lectures, radio and TV interviews, election campaign materials, and music.
Communist Party of the United States of America.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into five series:
Series I: Reel-to-Reel Audio Tapes: Meetings, 1967-1998 Series II: Reel-to-Reel Audio Tapes: Public Events, 1920s-1984 Series III: Audio Cassettes: Meetings, 1966-1999 Series IV: Audio Cassettes: Public Events, 1938-1999. Series: V: Audio Cassette Tapes, Mini-Discs, Mini-DV and VHS: Unprocessed Addendum
Items in Series I and III are arranged by governing body to reflect the organization of the Party. Items in Series II and IV are arranged chronologically. Series V has not been arranged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Communist Party of the USA Audio Collection was transferred to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives as part of the donation of the Communist Party of the USA archives and the Library of the Reference Center for Marxist Studies in the summer of 2006. A group of additional materials, clearly from the collection of materials in the first donation, was found at the Tamiment Library in May 2014, and added to the to the Collection. The accession number associated with this addition is 2014.109. Two additional taps were found in the repository and added to the collection in 2015.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that already have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.
Access Restrictions
All materials described in the finding aid are open to researchers without restriction. A small amount of material in the collection is not described in the finding aid and is restricted for a period of 25 years: it will open for research in 2037.
Scope and Content Note
This collection is comprised of the miscellaneous audio tapes (both reel-to-reel tapes and audio cassettes), and a small amount of video, stored in various offices at the New York headquarters of the Communist Party, USA and transferred to the Tamiment Library, NYU in the summer of 2006. Included are recordings of official meetings of the Party at the national level, such as National Conventions, and Central Committee and Political Bureau meetings, as well as meetings of district, state, local, youth and special-interest organizations. Also included are recordings of rallies, public meetings, conferences, lectures, radio and television interviews, election campaign materials, and music. The collection represents a unique resource for the study of internal Communist Party, USA decisions regarding policy, organization and education, and also documents the cultural life and public presentations of the Party, with particular emphasis on Party involvement in and reaction to civil rights and labor movements. Speakers include official Party representatives such as Gus Hall, Herbert Aptheker, Angela Davis, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, James Jackson, Jarvis Tyner, Charlene Mitchell, and Henry Winston. The tapes also include a wide range of other notable individuals, including W. E. B. Du Bois, Paul Robeson, Studs Terkel, Pete Seeger, Jesse Jackson, Hosea Hudson, Huey P. Newton, Fred Hampton, Ossie Davis, Albert Shanker, Richard Nixon, Rosalyn Baxandall, Vivian Gornick and many others. Included in the collection are a number of tapes recorded in the Soviet Union, South Africa and Cuba.
A number of items in the collection have accompanying speakers’ lists or other detailed notations on paper. Items with paper documentation are indicated in the finding aid with an asterisk (*). These paper materials are found in Subseries IV:F.
NOTE: Items in this collection must be digitized prior to researcher use. Please note that many reel-to-reel and cassette tapes are in poor condition. The majority of reel-to-reel tapes will require preservation work prior to digitization. Cassette tapes obviously requiring preservation work are individually noted in the finding aid, although other cassettes may also present digitization challenges.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Communist Party of the United States of America Records (TAM 132)
Communist Party of the USA Printed Ephemera Collection (PE 031)
Reference Center for Marxist Studies Pamphlet Collection (PE 043)
The Daily Worker and The Daily World Negatives Collection (PHOTOS 223.1)
The Daily Worker and The Daily World Photographs Collection (PHOTOS 223)
The Daily Worker and The Daily World Cartoon Collection (GRAPHICS 024.001)
Communist Party of the United States of America Audio Collection (TAM 132.1)
Communist Party of the United States of America Oral Histories (OH 065)
Jefferson School of Social Science Records and Indexes (TAM 005)
Files of the Communist Party of the USA in the Comintern Archives, 1919-1943 (Microfilm R-7548)
Central Control Commission records, CPUSA, ca.1929-1953 (Microfilm R-7821)
The Daily Worker, 1924-1958 (Microfilm R-7083)
The Daily World, 1972-1990 (Microfilm R-7084)
See the Research Guide to Communist Party USA Collections in the Tamiment Library for more information.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Communist Party, USA was founded in 1919 by members of the left wing of the Socialist Party USA. The CPUSA played an important role in the labor movement, particularly in building the Congress of Industrial Organizations in the 1930s-1940s, and in struggles for civil rights for African Americans. The Party's cultural initiatives in the 1930s attracted a number of prominent artists and intellectuals, and its struggles to attain and maintain its legality were an important chapter in the history of U.S. civil liberties. Though the importance of the CPUSA declined after the 1950s, the Party remained active in the areas of anti-imperialism, civil rights, labor, peace, and women's rights.
AFL-CIO.; African National Congress.; Aptheker, Herbert, 1915-2003.; Black Panther Party.; Communist Party of the Soviet Union.; Communist Party of the United States of America (Calif.).; Communist Party of the United States of America (Ill.); Communist Party of the United States of America (Mich.).; Communist Party of the United States of America (New York).; Communist Party of the United States of America. National Labor Commission.; Communist Party of the United States of America. Negro Commission.; Communist Party of the United States of America. Southern California District.; Communist Party of the United States of America.; Daily World (New York, N.Y.).; Davis, Angela Y. (Angela Yvonne), 1944-; Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley; Hall, Gus; Jackson, James E., 1914-2007; National Alliance against Racist and Political Repression (U.S.).; People's weekly world (New York, N.Y.).; Political Affairs Magazine (New York, NY).; Robeson, Paul, 1898-1976.; Socialist Scholars Conference.; Tyner, Jarvis; W.E.B. Du Bois Clubs of America.; Winston, Henry, 1911-1986.; Young Communist League of the U.S.; Young Workers Liberation League.; African American communists.; African Americans in the performing arts.; Audiocassettes.; Audiotapes.; Civil rights |z United States.; Communism |z California.; Communism |z New York (State) |z New York.; Communism |z New York (State).; Communism |z United States.; Communist education |z United States.; Communists |z New York (State); Communists |z New York (State) |z New York.; Communists |z United States |x Civil rights.; Elections |z United States |x History |y 20th century.; Labor unions and communism |z United States.; Political ballads and songs |z United States.; Political campaigns.; Videocassettes.; Women communists |z United States.; Youth movements |z United States.
- Series I: Reel-to-Reel Audio Tapes: Meetings, 1967-1998; 14.0 boxes
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I: Reel-to-Reel Audio Tapes: Meetings, 1957-1998, consists of reel-to-reel recordings of official meetings of the Communist Party, USA. These meetings were attended by Party members and guests and were not open to the public.
  Subseries I:A: National, 1957-1986 Central authority of the Communist Party, USA is vested in the National Convention, held every four years. Between National Conventions, the Central Committee has been the highest authority of the Party and directing all political, organizational and educational work, as well as supervising all departments and committees. This subseries contains recordings of the meetings of national governing bodies and commissions. Included in these meetings are internal reports, workshops, discussions, and speeches. Items are arranged by governing body, reflecting the internal structure of the Party.
  Subseries I:B: District and State, 1958-1975 Included in this subseries are meetings of district and state organizations, as well as District Convention,s during which delegates to the National Conventions are elected. Items are arranged alphabetically by district and state.
  Subseries I:C: Youth Organizations, 1964-1972 Youth organizations have been affiliated with the Communist Party since the early 1920s. The W. E. B. Du Bois Clusb, founded in 1964, became the Young Workers Liberation League five years later and remained active until 1983. The records of these two youth organizations are contained in this subseries.
  Subseries I:D: Miscellaneous, 1967-1980 Included in this subseries are Party forums, discussions, retreats and campaign committee meetings.
  - Subseries I:A: National
    - National Convention, 18th. Includes Gil Green, Dorothy Healey, James Jackson. New York, NY. Tape 1. [CPA #593], 1967 (Reel 132_0001, Box 1, Box 84)
    - National Convention, 18th. Includes James Allen, William Weinstone. New York, NY. Tape 2. [CPA #592], 1967 (Reel 132_0002, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 18th. Includes Trade Unions, Negroes. New York, NY. Tape 3.1. [CPA #945], 1967 (Box 1, Reel 132_0003)
    - National Convention, 18th. Includes Trade Union discussions. New York, NY. Tape 3.2. [CPA #526], 1967 (Reel 132_0004, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 18th. Includes Bettina Aptheker, Herbert Aptheker, Gil Green (?), James Jackson (?), Arnold Johnson, Al Richmond (?). New York, NY. Tape 4. [CPA #508], 1967 (Box 84, Reel 132_0005, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 18th. Includes (William Weinstone, Jim West). New York, NY. Tape 5. [CPA #567], 1967 (Box 84, Reel 132_0006, Box 1)
    - [National] Convention, 19th. "Singing at end of 19th Convention." New York, NY. [CPA #692], 1969 (Reel 132_0424, Box 14, Box 84)
    - Special Convention. Tape 1. [CPA #292], Jul 4, 1968 (Reel 132_0007, Box 1)
    - Special Convention. Includes James Jackson, Pat Toohey, Jim West. Tape 2. [CPA #288], Jul 5, 1968 (Reel 132_0008, Box 1)
    - Special Convention. Includes Kendra Alexander, Herbert Aptheker, Jesus Colon, James Jackson, William Patterson. Tape 3. [CPA #294], Jul 5, 1968 (Reel 132_0009, Box 1)
    - Special Convention. Includes Jesus Colon, Al Richmond. Tape 4. [CPA #295], Jul 5, 1968 (Reel 132_0010, Box 1)
    - Special Convention. Includes Franklin Alexander, Al Richmond. Tape 5. [CPA #290], Jul 6, 1968 (Reel 132_0011, Box 1)
    - Special Convention. Tape 6. [CPA #291], Jul 6, 1968 (Reel 132_0012, Box 1)
    - Special Convention. Includes Herbert Aptheker, Rose Chernin, Dynamite Hallinan, Dorothy Healey, Al Richmond. Tape 7. [CPA #289], Jul 7, 1968 (Reel 132_0013, Box 1)
    - Special Convention. Includes (Louise or William?) Patterson, John Pittman. Tape 8. [CPA #293], Jul 7, 1968 (Reel 132_0014, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 20th. New York, NY. Tape 1. [CPA #538], Feb 18, 1972 - Feb 21, 1972 (Reel 132_0015, Box 1, Box 84)
    - National Convention, 20th. Includes Carl Bloice, James Jackson, Charlene Mitchell. New York, NY. Tape 2. [CPA #541], Feb 18, 1972 - Feb 21, 1972 (Reel 132_0016, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 20th. Includes Puerto Rican [Communist Party?]. New York, NY. Tape 3. [CPA #540], Feb 18, 1972 - Feb 21, 1972 (Reel 132_0017, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 20th. Includes Carl Bloice, Japanese Americans. New York, NY. Tape 4. [CPA #535], Feb 18, 1972 - Feb 21, 1972 (Reel 132_0018, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 20th. New York, NY. Tape 5. [CPA #537], Feb 18, 1972 - Feb 21, 1972 (Reel 132_0019, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 21st. Includes Bettina Aptheker, Herbert Aptheker, James Jackson. Chicago, IL. Tape 1. [CPA #532], Jun 26, 1975 - Jun 29, 1975 (Reel 132_0024, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 21st. Includes Angela Davis Defense Workshop, John Pittman. Chicago, IL. Tape 2. [CPA #531], Jun 26, 1975 - Jun 29, 1975 (Box 84, Reel 132_0025, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 21st. Includes Angela Davis, James Jackson, John Pittman. Chicago, IL. Tape 3. [CPA #530], Jun 26, 1975 - Jun 29, 1975 (Box 62, Cd 26 (disks 1-8), Reel 132_0026, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 21st. Chicago, IL. Tape 4. [CPA #529], Jun 26, 1975 - Jun 29, 1975 (Reel 132_0027, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 21st. Chicago, IL. Tape 5. [CPA #533], Jun 26, 1975 - Jun 29, 1975 (Reel 132_0028, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 21st. Includes Gil Green, Arnold Johnson, Betty Smith, and Gus Hall, on Poetry. Chicago, IL. Tape 1. [CPA #536], Jun 26, 1975 - Jun 29, 1975 (Reel 132_0029, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 22nd. Rally. Detroit, MI. Tape 1 of 3. [CPA #285], Aug 26, 1979 (Reel 132_0030, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 22nd. Rally. Detroit, MI. Tape 2 of 3. [CPA #286], Aug 26, 1979 (Reel 132_0031, Box 1)
    - National Convention, 22nd. Rally. Detroit, MI. Tape 3 of 3. [CPA #287], Aug 26, 1979 (Reel 132_0032, Box 1)
    - Unidentified Convention. Discussion on Resolution on Black Capitalism; Charlene Mitchell, Report on the South; Also Includes Kendra Alexander. Tape 2. [CPA #360], undated (Reel 132_0400, Box 13)
    - Unidentified Convention. Black Liberation Discussion (continued); Claude Lightfoot's summation of discussion; Resolutions on Black Liberation; Gus Hall, Report on Leadership. Tape 13. [CPA #339], undated (Reel 132_0398, Box 13)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Dynamite Hallinan, Joseph North. Tape 1 of 3. [CPA #583], May 13, 1972 - May 15, 1972 (Reel 132_0099, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Si Gerson, and Jim West. Tape 2 of 3. [CPA #472], May 13, 1972 - May 15, 1972 (Reel 132_0100, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 3 of 3. [CPA #584], May 13, 1972 - May 15, 1972 (Reel 132_0101, Box 4)
    - Central Committee/National Council Meeting. Includes James Jackson, Arnold Johnson, and Jim West. Tape 1 of 3. [CPA #673], Sep 8, 1972 - Sep 10, 1972 (Reel 132_0102, Box 4)
    - Central Committee/National Council Meeting. Includes Bettina Aptheker, and James Jackson. Tape 2 of 3. [CPA #685], Sep 9, 1972 (Reel 132_0103, Box 4)
    - Central Committee/National Council Meeting. Tape 3 of 3. [CPA #722], Sep 8, 1972 - Sep 10, 1972 (Reel 132_0104, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 1. [CPA #683], Dec 8, 1972 (Reel 132_0105, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Herbert Aptheker, James Jackson, Arnold Johnson, and William Weinstone. Tape 2. [CPA #680], Dec 8, 1972 (Reel 132_0106, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Angela Davis, Gil Green, James Jackson, and Sandy Patrinos. Tape 3. [CPA #682], Dec 8, 1972 - Dec 10, 1972 (Box 62, Cd 107 (disks 1-8), Reel 132_0107, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes James Jackson. Tape 4. [CPA #686], Dec 10, 1972 (Reel 132_0108, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Herbert Aptheker, James Jackson, and Jim West. Tape 1. [CPA #681], Jun 2, 1973 - Jun 3, 1973 (Reel 132_0109, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Herbert Aptheker. Tape 2. [CPA #675], Jun 2, 1973 - Jun 3, 1973 (Reel 132_0110, Box 4)
    - Central Committee/National Council Meeting. Includes Herbert Aptheker, Angela Davis, Sandy Patrinos, and Jim West. Tape 1. [CPA #676], Dec 1, 1973 (Reel 132_0111, Box 4, Box 63, Cd 111 (disks 1-8))
    - Central Committee/National Council Meeting. Includes James Jackson, Resolution on (the expulsion of) Dorothy Healey. Also includes Al Richmond and John Pittman]. Tape 2. [CPA #677], Dec 2, 1973 (Reel 132_0112, Box 4)
    - Central Committee/National Council Meeting. Includes Arnold Johnson. Tape 3. [CPA #687], Dec 3, 1973 (Reel 132_0113, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Herbert Aptheker, Angela Davis, Arnold Johnson, and James Jackson. Tape 1. [CPA #679], Jun 29, 1974 - Jul 1, 1974 (Reel 132_0116, Box 4, Box 63, Cd 116 (disks 1-8))
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 2. [CPA #684], Jun 29, 1974 - Jul 1, 1974 (Reel 132_0115, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Herbert Aptheker, Arnold Johnson, Sandy Patrinos, Jim West, and William Weinstone. Tape 1. [CPA #678], Dec 7, 1974 - Dec 9, 1974 (Reel 132_0114, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Angela Davis and Sandy Patrinos. Tape 2. [CPA #511], Dec 7, 1974 - Dec 9, 1974 (Reel 132_0117, Box 4, Box 84)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes James Jackson. Tape 3. [CPA #669], Dec 7, 1974 - Dec 9, 1974 (Reel 132_0118, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Jim West. Tape 2. [CPA #512], Oct 5, 1975 (Reel 132_0119, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Gil Green, James Jackson, Arnold Johnson, and Sandy Patrinos. Tape 3. [CPA #539], Oct 5, 1975 (Reel 132_0120, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Jim West. Tape 1. [CPA #518], Nov 19, 1976 - Nov 21, 1976 (Reel 132_0121, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 2. [CPA #515], Nov 19, 1976 - Nov 21, 1976 (Reel 132_0122, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Herbert Aptheker, Angela Davis, and Arnold Johnson. Tape 3. [CPA #513], Nov 19, 1976 - Nov 21, 1976 (Reel 132_0123, Box 4, Box 63, Cd 123 (disks 1-4))
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes John Abt. Tape 4. [CPA #514], Nov 19, 1976 - Nov 21, 1976 (Reel 132_0124, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Frank Irezarry (Head of the Puerto Rican Communist Party), and John Pittman. Tape 5. [CPA #519], Nov 19, 1976 - Nov 21, 1976 (Reel 132_0125, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. New York, NY. Tape 1. [CPA #721], Dec 3, 1977 (Reel 132_0126, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 2. [CPA #720], Dec 3, 1977 (Reel 132_0127, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Gus Hall (Master, 37 min). Tape 1. [CPA #564], Dec 2, 1978 (Reel 132_0128, Box 4)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Gus Hall (Master, 75 min). Tape 2. [CPA #563], Dec 2, 1978 (Reel 132_0129, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 1. [Dubbing] [CPA #566], Dec 6, 1978 (Reel 132_0130, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 2. [Dubbing] [CPA #565], Dec 6, 1978 (Reel 132_0131, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Gus Hall at Reed. [CPA #562], Dec 1978 (Reel 132_0132, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Henry Winston. [CPA #615], Mar 10, 1979 (Reel 132_0133, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Gus Hall, Summaries (57 min). [CPA #661], Mar 12, 1979 (Reel 132_0134, Box 5)
    - Central Committee/National Committee Meeting. Report on Organization (69 min). [CPA #428], Mar 12, 1979 (Reel 132_0135, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Si Gerson, on the 1980 elections (38 min). [CPA #660], Nov 17, 1979 (Reel 132_0136, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Gus Hall, Report. Tape 1. [CPA #655], Jun 7, 1980 (Reel 132_0137, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Gus Hall, Summary. Tape 3. [CPA #656], Jun 8, 1980 (Reel 132_0138, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 4. [CPA #644], Jun 1981 (Reel 132_0139, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Gus Hall, Main Report. [CPA #662], Dec 12, 1981 - Dec 13, 1981 (Reel 132_0140, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Gus Hall, Summary. Tape 4. [CPA #654], Dec 13, 1981 (Reel 132_0142, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Discussion and Henry Winston, Report. Tape 4. [CPA #657], Dec 14, 1981 (Reel 132_0143, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Henry Winston, Report (continued). Tape 6. [CPA #658], Dec 12, 1981 - Dec 14, 1981 (Reel 132_0141, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 1. [CPA #648], May 28, 1983 - May 30, 1983 (Reel 132_0144, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Gil Green. Tape 2. [CPA #652], May 28, 1983 - May 30, 1983 (Reel 132_0145, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes James Jackson. Tape 3. [CPA #647], May 28, 1983 - May 30, 1983 (Reel 132_0146, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Elsie Dickerson, Si Gerson, and Sandy Patrinos. Tape 4. [CPA #649], May 28, 1983 - May 30, 1983 (Reel 132_0147, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes Angela Davis and Rose Kryzak. Tape 5. [CPA #653], May 28, 1983 - May 30, 1983 (Reel 132_0148, Box 5, Box 63, Cd 148 (disks 1-3))
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 6. [CPA #651], May 28, 1983 - May 30, 1983 (Reel 132_0149, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Includes J.J. Johnson. Tape 7. [CPA #650], May 28, 1983 - May 30, 1983 (Reel 132_0150, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 4. [CPA #659], Jan 22, 1984 (Reel 132_0151, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 1. [CPA #728], Dec 15, 1984 (Reel 132_0152, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 2. [CPA #725], Dec 15, 1984 (Reel 132_0153, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Tape 3. [CPA #727], Dec 16, 1984 (Reel 132_0154, Box 5)
    - Central Committee meeting, Dec 16, 1984 (Reel 132_0817, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Gus Hall, Main Report. Tape 1A. [CPA #726], Jan 18, 1986 (Reel 132_0155, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Henry Winston and Gus Hall, Summary. Tape 2. [CPA #707], Jan 1986 (Reel 132_0156, Box 5)
    - Central Committee Meeting. Gus Hall. Tape 5. [CPA #646], Oct 28 (Reel 132_0157, Box 5)